play.com 2013-05-25

# 

Dated March 2013.

We take our commitment to your privacy seriously and treat any information you supply to us with care.

  * Policy statement
  * The data we collect
  * Use of data
  * Marketing Preferences
  * Links to other websites
  * Reviews/Feedback
  * Surveys and user groups
  * Competitions
  * Email a friend
  * Use of Cookies
  * What types of activity do we use cookies for?
  * First and Third Party Cookies
  * Accepting and deleting cookies

#####  Policy statement

In relation to the website: www.play.com (‘the Site’). 

The Site is a Jersey-based website owned by Play Limited and complies with the Data Protection (Jersey) Law of 2005 relating to the personal information you supply online. 

PlayTrade S.à.r.l ('PlayTrade') and PlayMedia S.à.r.l ('PlayMedia'), both at 4-6 Avenue de la Gare L-1610 Luxembourg are its wholly owned subsidiaries. 

Any personal information that you provide to Play Limited, PlayTrade and PlayMedia whilst contracting with these entities is stored and controlled by Play Limited, located at 3rd Floor, 1 Esplanade, St Helier, Jersey JE2 3QA.

For the purposes of Luxembourg's legislation on Data Protection and particularly the law of August 2nd 2002, Play Holdings Limited is the Data Controller, whilst PlayTrade and PlayMedia are Data Processors. The information you provide to Play Limited, PlayTrade and PlayMedia may be shared with other companies controlled by the PlayHoldings group that are either subject to this Privacy Policy or follow practices that offer the same level of protection as those described herein.

^ Top

#####  The data we collect

The information collected by the aforementioned entities when you register with us at the [www.play.com](http://www.play.com/) website is generally used to communicate with you and improve our services where possible, and specifically, to process payments or enable third parties to carry out technical or commercial supporting functions. These functions may be carried out by us or appointed third parties who are bound by Data Protection covenants and must process the personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the Data Protection Laws of Luxembourg.

In addition to personal data such as name, e-mail address, delivery address, billing address, telephone number, credit or debit card number and expiry date, we also analyse data about participants in order to provide a safe shopping environment for all users. Examples of the data we may collect and analyse include the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, login, password, computer and connection information such as browser type and version, your operating system and platform, the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from our website (including date and time), cookie number, products you viewed or searched for, your purchase history, personal preferences and any phone number recorded or used to call our customer services number. 

We will not sell, distribute or disclose information about you or your personal usage of the Site without your express consent or unless required or permitted to do so by law. 

^ Top

#####  Use of data

We may monitor customer traffic patterns, Site usage and related Site information in order to optimise your use of the Site and we may give aggregated statistics to a reputable third-party, but these statistics will include no information personally identifying you.   We may combine your information with information lawfully obtained from other third party sources and use it to optimise your use of the Site and improve our services to you.

We may also use the Information we gather to notify you about important functionality changes and alterations to the Site, or offers of products, services or information that might be of particular interest to you.  

We may share the information we gather with trusted business and technical partners for operational purposes such as handling orders, delivering products and services, processing credit and debit card payments, sending communications, providing customer service functions, for fraud detection services and for data analysis.  Those of our partners who need to access personal information perform their business services, may not use the data for other purposes. 

Where you are involved in a transaction with a Seller/Merchant (third party who sells items through play.com website) your email address, postal address and contact information may be shared with the Seller/Merchant for the purpose of completing the transaction for which it is received. You will also receive emails from the Seller/Merchant confirming the order, including dispatch or eventual refund, and follow-up invitations to leave feedback for the Seller/Merchant.  You agree to receive these emails and accept that this does not breach any privacy requests. During any contact with Sellers/Merchants, we strongly encourage you to ask questions before you disclose personal information which the Seller/Merchant may not have obtained during the process of the order.

All payments are handled by Play.com; you should not buy directly through a Seller/Merchant.  Sellers/Merchants must never ask a buyer for payment card details, bank details or other payment method details.

We may also share data with law enforcement agencies and/or third parties in respect of information requests for criminal investigations and alleged illegal activities.  The personal information we disclose may include your name, billing/delivery address, telephone number, email address, and order history.

In case any fraudulent activity is detected on the website, or, without limitation, in connection with the breach of intellectual property rights through the use of the website, we may release personal information in order to comply with any applicable regulation or assert our rights as well as our business partners’.

Your information may also be transferred to another company in the event of sale of our company to a third party. 

All business/technical partners, Sellers/Merchants and Third Parties are bound by Data Protection covenants and must process the personal information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and the Data Protection Laws of Luxembourg. In the event that we need to transfer your information outside the European Union in accordance with this privacy policy, we will endeavour to ensure that your rights and freedoms in respect of the processing of your personal data are adequately and appropriately protected.

In using the site to buy and sell items, you expressly accept that your personal data may be used and transferred in accordance with this privacy policy.

^ Top

#####  Marketing Preferences

When you set up your account you will be given an opportunity to set your communication preferences. 

You can update your preferences at any time by logging into your account – a communication preferences tab appears on your account page. Here you can amend the email marketing messages you may wish to receive from Play.com and/or our Sellers/Merchants. Each time you make a purchase from one of our Sellers/Merchants you will also have the opportunity to select the emails you receive from that Seller/Merchant.

By subscribing to our mailing lists, you accept that your personal data may be used for such purposes. Sellers/Merchants on the Play.com website may contact you about products they sell on the Play.com website. By subscribing to their mailing lists, you are consenting to receive these marketing emails. 

If at any time you wish to stop receiving our newsletter or any other information you may have requested from us or any other company, please contact us or click the Unsubscribe link at the bottom of any e-mail you receive from us.

^ Top

#####  Links to other websites

Please note that we do provide links to other sites, which may not be governed by this Privacy Policy and you should view the respective privacy policies of those sites for further information.

Participants have the right to access their stored data, to rectify them if required and to object to the storage of their data for legitimate purposes. We would like to keep your information up-to-date, you may change any of the basic information we keep about you at any time by e-mailing us at [privacy@play.com](mailto:privacy@play.com).

^ Top

#####  Reviews/Feedback

Sellers/Merchants who you have placed an order with, may contact you for feedback purposes.

Beside any submitted ‘customer review’ or ‘Seller/Merchant feedback’ you place, your ‘nickname’ is displayed and is available to view by the public.

^ Top

#####  Surveys and user groups

We always aim to improve the services we offer. As a result we occasionally canvass our customers using surveys, provided that they have given their prior and express consent. Participation in surveys is voluntary, and you are under no obligation to reply to any survey you might receive from us. Should you choose to do so, we will treat the information you provide with the same high standard of care as all other customer information. 

^ Top

#####  Competitions

Your participation on our website may mean that we occasionally contact you with the opportunity to enter competitions. Entry to competitions is voluntary, and you are under no obligation to take up an invitation from us to enter. Should you choose to enter a competition, we will treat the information you provide with the same high standard of care as all other customer information, and use the information provided strictly within the entry terms of the competition and this Privacy Policy.

^ Top

#####  Email a friend

We operate an ‘Email a friend’ service. This is a referral service, designed to make it easy for customers to recommend our Site and related websites or offers to a friend, and is a two-step process. First, a customer sends us the friend's name and email address, and secondly, we contact the friend, telling them who we are, and inviting them to take advantage of a particular offer, or to visit our website. When we contact your friend, we always advise them of the name and email address of the friend who made the original referral. We will not use your friend’s details for any other purpose.

When a customer wishes to sponsor a friend and provides us with his/her name and e-mail address, we reasonably assume that such customer has obtained his/her friend's prior consent in order for us to process his/her data. Customers supply such information freely and voluntarily, under their sole responsibility.

^ Top

#####  Use of Cookies

In addition to the information which you supply to us, information and data may be automatically collected through the use of cookies.

Cookies are small text files, with ID tags that are stored on your device (computer/ mobile/ tablet) when visiting certain websites. Cookies keep track of your movements on the site to track what’s in your shopping basket and provide functions to improve your shopping experience. 

To order products on the Play.com website you need cookies enabled. Internet cookies are common and won’t cause any harm to your device. No personally identifiable information is stored within cookies; therefore we recommend you leave these switched on.  You can configure your Internet browser to accept or reject certain cookies or inform you when a cookie is saved.

We do not cross the information recorded in the cookies with the personal information collected at the time of your registration on the Site or with your online activity. 

Some of our business partners may themselves use cookies on their own websites. We have no access or control of these cookies; therefore we cannot accept liability for any malfunctioning of your PC or its installed web browser as a result of your access to any of the websites. 

Web Beacons, also called Pixel Tags or Clear Gifs are used in combination with cookies to understand the behaviour of customer.  A web beacon is typically a transparent graphic image (1 x 1 pixel) placed on a site or in an email.  Although Web beacons provide similar functions to cookies, Web Beacons are not placed on your computer.  If you turn off cookies, web beacons will simply detect an anonymous website visit.

^ Top

#####  What types of activity do we use cookies for?

**• Shopping Basket (Strictly Necessary Cookies)**  
Some cookies are essential during online transactions, e.g. to remember what products you have put in your shopping basket as you navigate to different pages on the website. These cookies are “strictly necessary” for the operation of the website. 

**• Improve user experience on the website (functionality cookies)**   
Cookies are used to remember your preferences on the site, such as currency preferences. These cookies are not shared with other websites. 

**• Profiling (targeting and advertising)**   
We use cookies to enable us to serve more targeted advertising to our customers on the Play.com website and on other partner websites. By knowing a user’s browsing habits, including sites visited, we can show advertisements that are more targeted to the interests of our customers. 

**• Video content**   
Flash cookies (or Local Shared Objects) are used to display video content using Adobe Flash Player.

^ Top

#####  First and Third Party Cookies

Cookies can either be first party, which are associated with the host domain e.g. Play.com, or third party cookies from any other domain including web analytics and advertising services. 

**Cookie Name**

| 

**Cookie Purpose**  
  
---|---  
  
**ASP.NET_SessionId**

| 

This cookie allows our web servers to respond to your actions on the website such as "Add to basket" or browsing the website. The website wouldn't work for you without it.

Expires:  At end of session  
  
**Session**

| 

Account Logon cookie  
  
**PlayCurrency3**

| 

Currency GBP or Euro  
  
**PlayBasket, BasketSummary**

| 

Show items in your shopping basket  
  
**PlayLocale**

| 

This cookie is used to identify your location, based on your IP address.  
  
**PlayReferrer, PlayReturnVisit**

| 

These cookies show us how you found our website and from which website you came from.   
  
**PlayUsername**

| 

This cookie helps us identify you to provide personalised services  
  
**RecentlyViewed**

| 

This cookie details the last 3 products viewed by you on the website, which is displayed in the ‘Recently viewed’ area of the website   
  
**RecentlyViewedProductIds**

| 

This cookie details your recently viewed products (maximum 8 from any single category) on the website.  These products are viewed when you select ‘See all’ within  ‘Recently viewed’ items  
  
**uidp**

| 

This cookie is used to identify the user when placing a product review on the website.  
  
**Website#lang**

| 

Language preference  
  
**X-Mapping-bdacodkd**

| 

Client session management cookie   
  
**_#srchist, _#sess, _#vdf, _#uid, _#usid** , **_#slid, _#clkid, _#lps, _#tsa, _#env**

| 

Tracks the success of our online marketing activity via DC Storm - a third party who provides marketing analytics for Play.com. Website: <http://www.dc-storm.com/>

**_#srchist** :  Stores the history of traffic sources the user has arrived to the site by

**_#sess** :  Stores information about the session

**_#vdf** :  Visit definition, e.g. number of visits

**_#uid** :  Stores a user identifier (only within a site)

**_#usid :  **Segments users using randomly generated numbers into groups **  **

**_#slid** :  Unique sale ID

**_#clkid** :  Unique identifier for a click generating a landing

**_#lps** :  Flags that the last page was secure and therefore has no referrer

**_#tsa** :  Helps to identify and remove duplicate traffic sources 

**_#env** :  Flags whether the environment variables (screen size, browser etc) need to be collected

Further information on [DC Storm Cookies](http://dc-storm.com/en-uk/cookie-use/list-of-cookies/)  
  
**_utma, _utmb, _utmc, _utmz**

| 

These cookies enable the function of Google Analytics, which is used to track a user’s shopping activity on the Play.com website and enables us to improve website functionality and customer experience;

**_utma** :  Each unique browser that visits a page on our website is provided with a unique ID via this cookie.  Subsequent visits to the site via the same browser are recorded as belonging to the same visitor.   Please note:  If two different people sharing the same computer account and browser access the site, only one unique visitor ID is recorded even though two unique individuals accessed the site.

**_utmb** , **_utmc** :  Used to establish and continue a user session on the site. 

**_utmz** :  Stores the referral used by the visitor e.g. whether you visited the site directly, or visited us via a link (ad campaign, search engine etc.).

Further information at [Google Analytics Usage on Websites](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/gajs/cookie-usage)

Google Analytics [opt-out browser add-on](http://support.google.com/analytics/bin/answer.py?hl=en&answer=181881&topic=2919631&ctx=topic)  
  
**ACOOKIE, WT_DC, WT_FPC, WTLOPTOUT, JSESSIONID**

| 

These cookies enable the function of Webtrends. 

Webtrends is a web analytics and customer intelligence company, offering visitor intelligence and analytics solutions.  Webtrends measure online activities to enable us to better understand and serve our customers.

**ACOOKIE** :  Persistent cookie for visitor identification

**WT_DC** :  SmartView transition page tracking

**WT_FPC** :  Visitor identification

**WTLOPTOUT** :  Opt out of data collection

See [Webtrends Cookie Policy](http://webtrends.com/terms-policies/cookie-policy) for details on how to opt-out.  
  
**Third party cookies**   
Third party cookies are cookies from another domain (not Play.com). 

We don’t control the content of these cookies. Therefore, please review information about the cookies from the third-party websites. Examples of third parties who set cookies on play.com include; 

**Third Party**  
  
---  
  
**Criteo**

_(Cookie names:   uid, tst, dis, uic, evt, udc, udi)_

A banner advertising network that specialises in retargeting (Website: [http://www.criteo.com](http://www.criteo.com/)).

Present products that you viewed on Play.com and other related products via adverts when you visit other selected websites. 

Click the link for [Criteo Privacy Policy](http://www.criteo.com/us/privacy-policy), for details on how to prevent the ads being displayed. ** __**  
  
**ScoreCardResearch**

Market research to report on internet trends using anonymous demographic and internet usage information ****  
  
**Advertising networks used to deliver interactive advertising campaigns on partner websites.   These cookies track the types of content you have viewed to ensure adverts are as relevant to you as possible.**

Affectv 

Audience Science

247 Real Media

Atlas (atdmt.com)

eXelate Media

Google (AdWords, doublclick, InviteMedia)

Flashtalking 

Lijit 

Lotame 

MediaMath 

Quantcast

Right Media (Yahoo)  

rfihub

Rocketfuel

Scorecardresearch

Specificclick.net

Tribal Fusion

Turn 

ValueCkick Media ****  
  
^ Top

#####  Accepting and deleting cookies

To order products on Play.com you need to have your cookies enabled. 

If you decline cookies you may lose some of the beneficial website functions of cookies.  No personally identifiable information is stored within cookies. Therefore, **we recommend you leave these turned on.**

To check if cookies are enabled on your device, please follow the steps below. Alternatively, view your browser’s help pages or information on how to manage cookies at <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>

Microsoft Internet Explorer:

  * Click on Tools and then Internet Options
  * Select Privacy tab to view your settings
  * Move the slider to your preferred settings

Firefox

  * Click on Firefox button and then select Options
  * Select Privacy option
  * Check ‘Accept Cookies from sites’ to enable cookies or uncheck to disable cookies.

 Google Chrome

  * Click Settings
  * Click ‘Show advanced settings...’
  * Select ‘Content Settings’ within Privacy
  * Select your own preferred settings

Safari for Mac

  * Click on Safari, then select Preferences
  * Click Privacy to view Cookie preferences

Note:  Safari blocks third-party cookies by default

Flash Cookies

Flash cookies are managed differently to normal cookies.  To disable or delete a Flash cookie, see [Adobe Flash Play security and privacy](http://www.adobe.com/security/flashplayer/) (opens a new window).  Note:  Flash cookies are not used on the Play.com website.

## Mobile / Tablet Device

**iOS:   Safari**

| 

**Android 4.0/ICS**  
  
---|---  
  
  * From the Home screen choose Settings > Safari ****
  * Under Privacy Select ‘Accept Cookies’ to view if cookies are enabled ****

| 

  * Open Browser>Menu>Setting>Privacy and Security

^ Top
